Justice itself is put on trial
Sweet Country is a western, crime, thriller film directed by Warwick Thornton.
In 1929, an Australian Aboriginal stockman kills a white station owner
in self-defense and goes on the lam, pursued by a posse.
Sam Kelly, played by Hamilton Morris.
Sergeant Fletcher, played by Bryan Brown.
Fred Smith, played by Sam Neill.
Mick Kennedy, played by Thomas M. Wright.
Harry March, played by Ewen Leslie.
Judge Taylor, played by Matt Day.
Sweet Country is a 2017 Australian revisionist Western
drama film, directed by Warwick Thornton.
Set in 1929 in the sparsely populated outback of Central Australia (before the formation of the Northern Territory) and based on a series of true events, it tells a harsh
story against the backdrop of a divided society (between the Anglo-Celtic Australians and Indigenous Australians) during the interwar period in Australia.
It was first screened in the main competition section of the 74th Venice International Film Festival in September 2017
and after winning the Special Jury Prize award there, went on to win several awards internationally.
The film explores themes of australia, rape, court case, slavery, bible.
The tone is emotional and intense.